

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

India

🛮 (+91)9560948115 | 🗷 harshitsinghai77@gmail.com | 🌴 fictionally-irrelevant.vercel.app/ | 🖸 harshitsinghai77 | 🛅 harshitsinghai/ | 💆 @harshitsinghai77

Summary _

Software Engineer with experience in tech startups and consulting. Passionate about Machine Learning, Data Engineering, and Web3.

Programming Skills

Server Side Python, Go, Node.js, FastAPI, Django, Celery, REST API

Client Side React, Next.js, React-Native, Redux, Typescript, HTML/CSS, SASS

Database PostgreSQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB, Redis

Machine Learning Scikit-Learn, Pandas, Data Analytics, Generative Al, Keras, Kubeflow, MLOps

Data Engineering Airflow, PySpark, Glue, S3, EMR, Hive, Presto, PySQL **Other** AWS, Docker, Git, Problem Solving, Data Structures

Work Experience _____

Deloitte USI Gurugram, India

DATA ENGINEERING @DELOITTE USI - STRATEGY AND ANALYTICS - ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE AND DATA ENGINEERING

Feb. 2022 - Ongoing

- Working with Data Engineering team at Vanguard (USA)
- · Streamlined batch processing ETL jobs using AWS Glue, PySpark, SparkSQL, EMR and S3 data lake.
- · Worked closely with the analytics team and and various stakeholders to translate business needs into technical solutions.

Cliff.ai Indore, India

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Aug. 2021 - January 2022

- Improved the speed and reduced the memory usage of two micro-services.
- · Worked with a variety of technologies including Kafka, Elasticsearch, Clickhouse, MongoDB, and MySql.
- · Designed a scalable, fault-tolerant system utilizing producer-consumer architecture and parallel processing.

Deepsource Bengaluru, India

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER INTERN (6 MONTHS) - PLATFORM

December 2020 - June 2020

- Designed and implemented pipeline for automatic training, re-training, and deployment of 50k+ ML models.
- Utilized XGBoost for training and developed recommendation system for ranking relevant issues for each repository.
- Managed ML infrastructure and data engineering tasks."

MLH Fellowship - BentoML Remote, India

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTOR

Oct 2020 - Dec 2020

• Contributed to BentoML (https://github.com/bentoml/BentoML)

(1 // 0 / /

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN (6 MONTHS)

Finshots/Ditto Insurance

Bengaluru, India Jan. 2020 - May. 2020

• Developed the user-interface for both web app and mobile app (Android and iOS) using React, React Native, Redux and Typescript.

Projects

Click here to see all the projects

Side Project

LIST OF ALL THE SIDE PROJECTS I'VE SHIPPED.

Jun. 2021 - Ongoing

• https://fictionally-irrelevant.vercel.app/posts/side-projects-2022

Education

Bennett Univeristy 7.98 CGPA

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Delhi NCR. India

Aug. 2016 - Aug. 2020

• Main coursework: Data Structures, Machine Learning, Cloud, Data Engineer, Web3.

January 2, 2023 Harshit Singhai · Résumé